Liel Amar

E-mailliel@lielamar.comDate of birthMarch 18th, 2001Websitelielamar.comMobile+972 (54) 974-1803GitHubgithub.com/LielAmarAddressGilo, Jerusalem

Expert developer with 6+ years of experience in a variety of languages, technologies, large-scale systems, applications, and games. A natural leader with proven capabilities in team management, public assistance, employee nurturing and tutoring, creating and executing work plans. Creative, inquisitive, and autodidact.

Professional Experience

January 2021 - Current

Software Developer | ReWrite Media, North Carolina

- Developing games, cosmetics, tools, and features for Minecraft Servers, using Minestom, Spigot & Velocity.
- Designing UI and implementing Web applications using Java's Spring Boot, NodeJS with Express & React, and Amazon Web Services.
- Integrating Redis and MongoDB with a Message-Broker, using RabbitMQ.
- Working in a team and collaborating with other employees on a daily basis.

March 2015 - Current

Software Developer | Volunteer & Freelancer

- Developed React-based Web applications integrated with MongoDB & MySQL.
- Developed public libraries in various languages, including Java & TypeScript.
- Developed "Minestore", an integration system between Minecraft and NodeJS Web applications, that handles the selling of in-game perks and items.
- Developed "Cybernet's AS" A system to track attendance in community centers.
- Founder & developer of "Tsophen" A B2C Startup in the data protection field.
- Developing ServerStats An open-source project to track game servers data.

August 2019 - April 2020

Developer, Unit Co-Founder and Leader | Israel Defense Forces, Israel

- Designed, implemented, tested, deployed, and maintained a real-time location-based Web application and multiple Windows applications.
- Provided units with evaluations, demonstrations, and samples.
- Recruited, trained, and commanded soldiers, pushed their personal development.
- Collaborated with other brigades, shared resources, and knowledge.

July 2017 - July 2019

Developer, Video Editor | Oversight, Israel

- Managed and maintained 20 Spigot servers on Linux and Windows machines.
- Designed and developed 7 large-scale Minecraft minigames.
- Led weekly development meetings and monthly meetings with the volunteer team.

Volunteer Positions

July 2019 - May 2021

Staff Member | Hypixel

- Provided in-game assistance to players and general moderation.
- Trained and mentored new staff members.
- Found bugs and tested new updates, features, and minigames.

July 2016 - July 2019

Server Manager, Developer | Play-IL, Israel

- Recruited, trained, and guided new and old staff members.
- Developed new minigames, released updates, patched bugs, and exploits.
- Led weekly work meetings and monthly community events.

Other Skills

Video Editor, Designer

- Editing High-Quality videos and creating 3D Minecraft animations.
- Designing models, logos, banners, and pictures.

Education and Languages

2019 - Graduated with emphasis on Computer Science from "Ort's College" High-School, Jerusalem.

2020 - Design Patterns Course

Hebrew - Native language

English - Fluent speaker